SAMARTH GOELsamarth_goel2019@pgp.isb.edu | +91-8377911890
EDUCATION
EDUCATION
INDIAN SCHOOL OF BUSINESS û Top 25 in the Financial Times Global MBA Rankings 2021(Apr 2018 û Apr 2019)
PGP in Management | DeanÆs List | Top 10% amongst ~900 students | Major: Finance and Marketing
JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY(Jul 2007 û Feb 2012)
M.B.A.û Finance and Strategy, B. Tech.û Computer Science Engineering | Top 5% amongst 500 students
National winner (among 480 teams) of Analyst 2011, an Apple product go-to-market strategy case competition held at ABV-IIITM
Implemented Indian Sign Language interpreter using image processing and machine learning to help give speech to the mute
DELHI PUBLIC SCHOOL, VASANT KUNJ(1994 - 2007)
Gold medalist: Top 10% amongst ~600 students for 7 consecutive years CERTIFICATIONS
 CERTIFICATIONS
CFA (Chartered Financial Analyst) Level 1 from the CFA Institute
The Fundamental of Digital Marketing from Google Digital Unlocked
Google Analytics for Beginners from Google Analytics Academy
AI Generalist program from GrowthSchool
13 years of experience building B2B and B2C  products in fintech and financial services industry as product manager and business analyst across capital markets domain in US and Asia, and digital consumer, personal and MSME lending domain in India, while collaborating with  global, multicultural, and cross-functional teams. SUMMARY
 SUMMARY
On the hunt to hone my skills in building new and scaling existing businesses and products.
WORK EXPERIENCE
WORK EXPERIENCE
CLIX CAPITAL SERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED, GURUGRAM    (Dec 2022 û Present)
Assistant Vice President | Strategy & New Business Initiatives - CEOÆs Office | Co-lending Business | Product Head - Loan Against Property
Launching new products, setting up new businesses, digital transformation & managing Loan Against Property business
Conceptualized & launched high ROA product - Small Business Loan, and scaled up to monthly INR 10cr business in 4 months
CompanyÆs first scorecard based underwriting; short TAT; low touch processing; zero human resource ramp-up
Formed the basis of existing Upfront Reject in Business loans
Setup co-lending business, and scaled up from zero to monthly INR 50cr in 6 months with a lean team of three (2 management trainees)
Built a book of INR ~400cr in 12 months; contributed to 40% of companyÆs PAT (35cr) in FY25; established & managed 4 bank partners
Digital integration with 2 platforms & 3 banks; Developed automations identifying pool from book (to cover up for lack in sourcing)
Conducted company-wide digital & AI Initiatives
Self-developed DSA visit app: Centrally track 4000+ monthly SM DSA visits; INR 17 lacs worth fee collected digitally in 2 months
Zero cost to company; inculcate data driven decision making; Further to be used for self-incentive tracking & travel claims by SMs
Self-developed POC for automated real-time payment application for customer payments made via digital payment links
Eliminated 2 hours of daily manual effort; improved payment application accuracy; minimized reconciliation issues
Self-developed POC for AI caller for automated regular DSA reachout, engagement & Clix offering awareness: http://bit.ly/4ao1DAK
Self-developed POC for Clix LAP Policy Saarthi (RAG) AI Bot aimed at enhancing on-field salesforce effectiveness: https://bit.ly/4r8u7pu
Self-developed AI based utility to find nearby DSAs which could help Salesteam to prospect new DSAs: https://bit.ly/DSA-finder
Created AI generated audio-visual content for Clix:
Video for announcing the first prize winner of FY25 JFM contest with the help of an agency: https://bit.ly/Clix-winner
Clix Anthem for FY25 Offsite event: https://tinyurl.com/Clix-anthem
Self-developed AI agent for personal brand building as AI enthusiast & budding expert that generates & posts consented LinkedIn posts
Self-developed a personal AI curated newsletter to keep myself updated about industries of my interest: https://bit.ly/clix-briefs
Conducted knowledge sharing session on effective use of Generative AI and thought stimulation workshop for all Clix employees
Enhanced operational efficiency & per rupee disbursed income of Loan Against Property business
Designed & launched the companyÆs first Sales Management App
Enabling on-the-go 100% digital logins with on-demand CIBIL and banking check, and digital fee collection to enhance productivity
Enhanced digitalisation of LOS by enabling on-system initiation of eMandate and loan docket execution
Increased insurance PDR by 25 bps YoY & introduced new Legal & Technical Charges worth INR ~65 lacs per annum
Introduced & created new LAP products - GST Margin, LAP-BL Combo and 20-20-10 in line with the industry
Self-developed business dashboards directly integrated with LMS & LOS providing on-demand view of productivity, efficiency and profitability of LAP business saving 8 man hours daily & enabling data-driven decisioning and strategy formulation, at zero cost
DMI FINANCE PVT. LTD., NEW DELHI                                                                                                                                                  (May 2019 û Dec 2022)
Senior Product Manager | Digital Consumer, Personal and MSME Lending
Building and managing end-to-end customer loan journeys covering customer discovery, acquisition, onboarding, servicing and collections, and customer retention via cross and up selling. Benchmarking financial and tech products against competition.
Achieved loan book growth from INR 1200 crores to INR 4300+ crores in 3 years
With zero ramp up in human resources by ideating and building automation tools
Generated 4800X improvement and INR 60 crores per annum, in operational efficiency and business value, respectively
Increased monthly disbursals by 4X from INR 100 cr in H1 2022 to INR 400 cr in H1 2023 for Samsung, a strategic OEM partner by
Expansion into new product categories - Consumer Electronics & Tablets, and bundling related products û Warranty & Insurance
Expansion of sales channels û offline from 25K to 60K dealers, and online by launching on Samsung eStore
Improvement of conversion rates by 40% by extending sustenance of customerÆs interest via journey optimizations 
Established 100% digital API based partnerships with Servify (Apple reseller chain in India), Google Pay, Airtel, Jio, Reliance Retail Ltd.
Designed and executed targeted cross selling program increasing cross-sell monthly disbursals from INR 0 to INR 40 crores
Widened payment options from 4 to 20+ used for EMI collections by onboarding new payment partners, PGs and BBPS
Improved portfolio quality and KYC compliance by adopting AI based photo liveliness check on selfies
Developed 100% digital KYC stack handling all KYC types leveraging oKYC, Digilocker, AI driven OCR and facial recognition
Reduced false KYC rejects by 80% in acquisition funnel by solving for Aadhaar aging problem using analytics model and AWS
Enabled better underwriting for NTC customers by incorporating Account Aggregator into the loan application journey
CITIBANK, SINGAPORE(Jun 2014 - Apr 2018)
Assistant Vice President, IT Business Analyst | Institutional Clients Group û Operations and Technology
Fast growth trajectory in 3 years (vs average ~4.5 years): Assistant Manager->Manager->Assistant Vice President
Key accomplishments
Received Dazzle Award (awarded to 100 out of 80K) and USD 2000 as a token of appreciation for outstanding performance
Achieved rank 1 on the Wall Street for Citi Velocity, the bankÆs market intelligence platform used by 82K+ customers in 130 countries
15% increase in client engagement by redesigning UI and adding new features serving unserved end client needs
Problem-solving and strategic solution designing skills
Enabled sales traders to target sell financial products to 20,000+ clients by 2019 through development of stock recommendation engine
Ideated a framework to segment clients and generate machine learning and natural language processing based recommendations
Saved $ 2M in potential fines and loss of banking licenses to regulators in the USA and Hong Kong through root cause analysis
Proactively used findings from RCA to design strategic risk management and control solutions as preventive measures
Improved CitiÆs ranking to 1 from 35 amongst 4000+ global broker-dealers on regulatory scorecards through reporting automation
Leadership initiatives
Lead BA for Datawarehouse, CitiÆs golden source of global cross product trade and reference data used for regulatory reporting
Generated ~USD 1M (11%) annual savings in data license cost through development of an in-house centralized market data platform
Identified the opportunity, influenced senior management to invest and led the initiative
Achieved 30% reduction in teamÆs client servicing time through ideating and leading implementation of self-service projects
Led collaboration with 20+ teams to design a strategic messaging data model for order management and trading systems
Stakeholders managed
Internal: MDs, Business, product & trading desk heads, Sales & quant traders, Financial modelers, trading ops, UI/UX & technology teams
External: Regulators, Major partner broker-dealers, Major data vendors (Thomson Reuters, Bloomberg), Tech vendors and startups
HCL TECHNOLOGIES LTD., SINGAPORE(May 2012 - Jun 2014)
Business Analyst | Banking, Financial Services and Insurance Practice
Achieved accelerated career growth by offering a rare bundle of domain knowledge, technical and stakeholder management skills
Management Trainee->Associate Business Analyst->Business Analyst in 1 year (Average ~3 years); Achieved by 1 in 100+ trainees
Leadership initiatives, projects and stakeholder management
Managed a globally distributed team of 11 members, and clients across 4 continents during HCLÆs various client engagements
Secured a USD 150K follow-on engagement during management of client stakeholder relationships on key accounts 
Value creation for clients and peers
Improved a leading global banksÆ bottom line by USD 300M by enabling it to adopt client lifetime value-based relationship management
Ideated and developed an execution cost analytics tool to track individual trade profitability and reconcile invoices
Conducted 80+ hours of technical and functional training sessions for 8 business analysts and 50+ software developersSKILLS & INTERESTS
SKILLS & INTERESTS
Skills: Business Analysis, Requirement elicitation & gathering, PL/SQL, Data analysis, Data warehousing, VBA macros programming, .Net, APIs
Interests: Financial modeling, Business valuation, Strategy, Startups, Applied analytics, data science and AI, Programming, Product design, UX
COMMUNITY IMPACT & PERSONAL INTERESTS
COMMUNITY IMPACT & PERSONAL INTERESTS
Community Impact: Jamiyah ChildrenÆs Home, Singapore and South East Community Development Council (SECDC), Singapore
Led a team of 5 to develop formalized IT & life skills workshop program; Taught 30+ kids from domestically violent and abusive homes
Benefited 20+ elderly couples living alone by developing a pilot program for volunteers to visit and help clean their homes regularly
Sports: Avidly played lawn tennis, swimming and rowing (Citibank dragonboat racing team member); Currently pursuing pickleball
Traveling/driving: Traveled to 8+ countries in South East Asia, and 16/29 states in India; road-trips across Malaysia and Thailand
